ORIGINAL WORK BY TATSUYA ENDO
SERIALIZED ON SHUEISHA'S SHONEN JUMP PLUS
ONE DAY LAST MONTH
We reached an official agreement.
It will take effect next month
on the tenth.
President… My sympathies.
President, huh?
I guess I won’t be hearing that
much longer.
Desmond Group will…
Don't mention it.
We can’t resist it anymore.
Our business was already
in a precarious situation.
But how should I tell my son…
that Glooman Pharmaceuticals
will cease to exist in a month.
MISSION 19:
THE REVENGE PLOT AGAINST DESMOND
The days are so peaceful now that
the tests are done.
Anya was able to dodge the Tonitrus Bolts,
so Father is calm now.
What? Is Mr. Loid strict? Is he scary?
Father is a fiend…
concerning his mission.
He’s a perfectionist.
I see.
It’s hard for us kids when parents
expect too much of us. But…
a fiendish Mr. Loid is lovely too!
Desmond style…
Rolling Sweep!
You're amazing as always, Damian!
You cleaned up our school!
How amazing, Damian!
You even excel at cleaning!
You were spinning so fast!
He got a Stella Star with his
own abilities after all.
Of course.
Next time on our day off,
let’s have a study session
at Damian’s house.
-Let's get close to him!
-Me too!
Look at him getting all that attention.
I had newfound respect for him after
the test, but he’s just a brat after all.
Anya wants to go to the study session
at the second son’s house too.
So Anya, you’re really into him, right?
Into who?
I’m sorry for calling him a brat.
I hate him.
-Don't try to play dumb with me.
-Damian, take a look at my…
I won't forgive you, Desmond.
I really won't forgive you.
I brought the dustpan, Damian.
Thanks.
Who is that?
You mean George?
George Glooman. He's our classmate.
Why? Why did he get a Stella Star?
My plan failed!
I asked my butler to hire a spy
in order to make Damian fail his test.
This is three months' worth
of my allowance.
Hire a good spy with this.
Certainly.
What?
The mastermind behind the spy
was my classmate?
Is it the one Father fought against
the other day?
Forget about him and tell me
what you like about Damian.
Anya’s curious about him. Who is he?
What? Seriously? Anya, do you not care
as long as they’re boys?
You should stay away from him.
He looks so gloomy.
Don’t give up, George.
If I can get him expelled…
He’s trying to get the second son
expelled from school!
There's still chance left for me…
Oh look.
This is a cigarette butt.
Damian… Did you…?
What? I’ve never smoked before!
Teacher! Please come over here.
Hey, stop it!
I told you that it wasn't me!
What are you doing?
What's going on?
I found a cigarette,
so I tried to inform the teacher,
then he punched me all of a sudden.
-Ouch.
-What?
What did you say?
Explain yourself, Damian!
This is a serious problem!
Damian would never do something like that.
George is lying!
You guys are Damian’s followers.
Your words can't be trusted.
What?
The second son wouldn't do
anything like that. Anya was watching.
He tripped on his own.
What?
What is this? It seems as if her eyes
can see right through me.
This is the kid that got a Tonitrus Bolt
on the first day of school.
This is not good. This kid is trouble!
My instincts from 30 years
of teaching experience are telling me so!
Stop calling me over for your
childish games.
Concentrate on cleaning up.
You…
Anya would be in trouble
if the second son got expelled.
My plan B…
Anya, you were so cool!
My heart skipped a beat!
Skipped a beat?
I’m sure your feelings reached Damian too.
Right?
Huh? What are you saying?
I never asked you to help me!
-That was really unnecessary!
-That's right!
You ruined everything!
-Huh?
-What?
More importantly, what the hell is wrong
with you? What's your problem?
What do you have against me?
Damn it, it's all over now.
My life is over!
What?
Your family's company went bankrupt?
Yes. It happened today.
I'm sorry to hear that,
but that has nothing to do with me.
Our company was driven out of business,
by your company.
What?
Come to think of it,
I heard something about Desmond Group
and Glooman Pharmaceuticals on the news.
I thought that if you failed the test,
or got expelled,
your family would be distracted,
and our bankruptcy would be put on hold.
My father's company won't do anything evil
like drive a company out of business.
Don't drag me into the issues
between grown-ups!
He's right! You've gone too far!
You're absolutely right.
But the truth is, I have to leave this
school because of those grown-up issues.
What? You're leaving this school?
Since our family couldn't
evade bankruptcy,
we're going to end up
on the streets tomorrow.
Which means that I won't be able to
stay in this school.
I’m envious of you, Damian.
You were born into a privileged family
and you’re popular.
No wonder you got a Stella Star.
You're completely different
from a piece of trash like me.
Damian got that Stella Star
with his own abilities! It has nothing
to do with this family!
That's right! It's your fault
that you're not popular!
It's your gloomy character!
No way!
Hey.
His minions are jerks too.
Shut up! You guys will
never understand my feelings!
I wanted to enjoy my youth in this school!
But now that is nothing
but an empty dream!
Knowing that today is my last day,
makes cleaning even more meaningful!
Trash like me, is picking up trash.
You find this ironic, don't you?
Don't you?
No one is saying that.
Calm down.
Damn it. I'm going to curse
this entire world!
Cheer up.
I'll buy you some juice.
Juice won't fix anything, huh?
-I'm sorry.
-I want to drink some right now.
What?
I want juice.
Because today is my last day of school.
If I don't drink it now,
I'll never be able to…
I… I'll go buy some!
Oh… okay.
Thank you.
This made me feel a little better.
I'm glad.
Come to think of it,
I never got to order
the finest quality caviar rice bowl
at the cafeteria.
If I have to leave this school
without ever eating that,
I think my life will spiral out of control
with regret.
Oh, by the way,
I've always wanted to pin
the Stella Star on my shirt just once.
Can someone let me borrow one?
You little…
I was working hard towards
the Stella Star…
But ever since I heard about
the bankruptcy,
I can't concentrate on studying.
I know that it's unreasonable,
but my anger towards the Desmond Group
keeps taking control…
Wow!
Someone please take a picture of me!
Give it back right away.
Next, I want to…
Hey you! You better not get carried away!
Sometime next month,
my family will be penniless,
and I'll probably be sold off to Westalis
in some form of human trafficking.
That's where I will begin
my life as a slave.
I'm so pitiful.
So, can't you let me enjoy this
brief moment of happiness?
Or does trash like me not have
the right to do that?
Don't worry. The West is a safe country.
Father and his boss are both good people.
They have no idea what Westalis is like,
but they're trying to comfort me?
Everyone is so kind.
It's the first time anyone has
treated me so kindly.
What is this?
Salty water won't stop spilling
from my eyes.
George…
Can I ask you guys for one last favor?
I was looking forward to
the end-of-the-year school chorus.
I wanted to become one with everyone
by singing a song.
Can we do that?
It's impossible, huh?
Oh… Why are we feeling so emotional…?
Becky… Are you serious?
Everyone…
Everyone… Thank you so much!
Thank you for
this incredibly memorable moment.
George.
You can have this.
This is my favorite school stationery kit.
It's expensive.
Don't forget us,
even after you leave this school.
Damian!
Everyone…
You can have my favorite book.
I'll give you my watch.
Please treasure it.
Anya will give you a leaf
that was on the ground.
Work hard even when you go
to a different school!
Class Three will always be with you!
Thank you! I will work hard!
I will turn this pain into strength,
and continue living my life
filled with hardships,
without ever giving up!
Goodbye, everyone!
Goodbye Eden, my love!
…That's what happened today.
What a wonderful story!
I… I see.
But…
Glooman Pharmaceuticals is being
bought out. They're not going bankrupt.
What?
Our company was facing a financial crisis,
so Desmond Group saved us.
Management will change,
but they agreed to keep me
and the research team in the company.
I can't thank them enough for agreeing
upon terms that are favorable to us.
I lost my title as President,
along with the Glooman company name,
so I was at a loss as to how
I should explain everything to you.
Then…
What about my life as a slave in Westalis?
What about school?
What are you talking about?
Go to school tomorrow like you always do.
Did you do your homework?
You better return everything that
everyone gave you.
Pay me back for the juice too.
Anya, wake up or you'll be late.
Breakfast is ready,
so get changed and wash up.
Okey-dokey.
Oh no! I overslept!
Anya's in a crisis from early
in the morning!
Don't talk while you're eating.
Tardiness and forgetting things can
accumulate and get you into trouble.
You'll be expelled if you get
eight Tonitrus Bolts. Be careful.
You're so strict.
I'm so glad she made it on time.
I'll be heading off to the hospital now.
What about you, Yor?
I have the morning off today, so I'm going
to City Hall in the afternoon.
Then I guess you can relax a little.
Well, I'll be off.
Goodbye. Good luck at work.
It seems like Bond overslept today too.
Oh, is that…
Sorry Anya, I'm going to let myself in.
Oh no! She forgot to take this!
Anya Forger! You will be expelled
because you forgot your gym uniform!
Oh no!
No, Anya, you must not give up!
It will make Loid very sad!
I can't stay here like this!
I must take this to Anya!
MISSION 19: THE MOTHER BECOMES THE WIND
Let's see… Where's the bus stop?
That's not a school bus,
so I'll have to get off once
and transfer to another bus.
Oh, but wait. Which is faster?
The bus or the train?
What am I supposed to do…
Oh no, I'm just wasting time like this.
What if I don't make it in time
for her gym class?
What will happen then?
Oh.
Please excuse me.
Please wait for me, Anya!
I finally made it.
But where could Anya be?
I think she said that
her classroom changes with each class.
Tardiness and forgetting things can
accumulate and get you into trouble.
You'll be expelled if you get
eight Tonitrus Bolts.
That's right! The fact that
she forgot this has to be kept a secret!
Then that means that I can't ask anyone
for help.
I guess I'll have to find her on my own.
Hey have you heard about
the ghost that appears at Eden?
She's called "The Freaky Spider Woman."
You idiot. Such a thing does not exist…
LOOKING FOR ANYA
It's the spider woman!
I guess I need to stay hidden.
If I'm not careful,
someone might report me to the police.
I've got an idea!
I should put on a disguise.
Then I can freely walk around
and look for Anya.
-Teacher!
Help us solve this!
Wait… um…
No, let's not do that.
Isn't there any other way?
Oh, these are the animals that I saw
on the day of the admission interview.
This is not good! I might get caught!
Yor? What is she doing here?
Did she follow me because she found out
that I'm infiltrating the school
while pretending to be at work?
No, that can't be.
Hm? She's holding something.
Where are you, Anya?
Anya…
-Anya!
-Mother!
Stay quiet.
Anya, I'm so glad I found you.
Here. You forgot this.
Are you okay?
Did I make it in time for your gym class?
Hm?
Anya, is something the matter?
We don't have gym class today.
-Huh?
-So, I don't need this gym uniform.
What?
No way…
Well…
I guess it turned out well,
since she didn't forget anything.
Yor!
Loid! Didn't you go to the hospital?
Yes, after I went to the hospital,
I visited a patient who's
receiving treatment at home.
And what are you doing here, Yor?
Well, the truth is…
I see. You went to deliver something
that you thought Anya forgot.
Thank you.
I was wondering what had happened,
but I guess I didn't really need to
come back to find out.
Not at all.
In the end, it was my misunderstanding,
so I was completely useless.
I should have known her schedule
to begin with.
I have failed as a mother.
That's not true.
If Yor becomes depressed,
it will affect my mission.
By the way,
I was thinking of
eating lunch before heading back to
the hospital. You're here.
-So, would you like to join me?
-Yes.
There's a place near here
that serves delicious lunch.
Wow, I can't wait!
MISSION 20: INVESTIGATE THE GENERAL
HOSPITAL/DECIPHER THE ARCANE CIPHERS
Subtitle translation by: Lili Morita